水蜡树街
我早该想到会在这里见到你
I should've known that you would be here
麦格教授
Professor McGonagall
晚安 邓布利多教授
Good evening Professor Dumbledore
传闻是真的吗 阿不思
Are the rumors true Albus
我想是真的 教授
I'm afraid so professor
有好消息 也有坏消息
The good and the bad
那个孩子了 海格会把他带到这儿来
And the boy Hagrid is bringing him
你觉得这么做明智吗 把这种大事交给海格去办
Is it wise to trust Hagrid with something so important
教授 我可以把自己的命 交到海格手中
Professor I would trust Hagrid with my life
邓布利多教授 麦格教授
Professor Dumbledore sir Professor McGonagall
没遇到什么麻烦吧 海格 没有 先生
No problems I trust Hagrid No sir
小家伙一飞到布里斯托就睡了
Little tyke fell asleep as we were flying over Bristol
小心别吵醒他
Try not to wake him
你看
There you go
你觉得把他交给这些人好吗
Do you really think it's safe leaving him with these people
我在这里观察了一整天
I've watched them all day
真是一群无可救药的麻瓜
They're the worst sort of Muggles
他们真的是 他在世上唯一的亲人
They really are The only family he has
这孩子将来会非常有名
He'll be famous
我们世界中的每个孩子 都会知道他的名字
Every child in our world will know his name
完全正确
Exactly
最好是让他成长时远离这一切
He's far better off growing up away from all of that
等他能够接受的时候再告诉他
Until he's ready
好了 好了 海格
There there Hagrid
又不是再也见不到面
It's not really goodbye after all
德思礼夫妇敬启 萨里郡小惠因区水蜡树街四号
祝你好运
Good luck
哈利波特
Harry Potter
起来 起床了
Up Get up
快呀
Now
快醒呀 表弟 要去动物园了
Wake up cousin We're going to the zoo
喔 我们的小寿星来了 生日快乐 儿子
Here he comes the birthday boy Happy birthday son
快去煮早餐 不准烧焦东西
Cook breakfast And try not to burn anything
是 佩妮阿姨
Yes Aunt Petunia
我希望今天一切顺心
I want everything to be perfect
这可是我们达力的大日子
for my Dudley's special day
快呀 给我咖啡 小子
Hurry up Bring my coffee boy
是 威农姨夫
Yes Uncle Vernon
是不是很棒呀 亲爱的
Aren't they wonderful darling
一共有几个 三十六个 我自己数的
How many are there 36 Counted them myself
三十六个 但去年有三十七个
36 But last year I had 37
但有些礼物比去年的大一点呀
But some are bigger than last year's
我管它有多大
I don't care
好 好 待会儿我们一出去
This is what we're going to do
就再去替你买两个新礼物 好不好呀 小乖乖
We're going to buy you two new presents How's that pumpkin
快到动物园了 一定可以玩得很开心 真期待
It should be a lovely day at the zoo I'm really looking forward to it
我警告你 小子
I'm warning you now boy
要是有任何怪事发生 只要有一点点的怪事
Any funny business any at all
你就一个礼拜不准吃饭
and you won't have any meals for a week
上车
Get in
爬虫类馆
叫它动嘛
Make it move
动呀
Move
快动呀 它在睡觉
Move He's asleep
它无聊死了
He's boring
对不起 他不了解你的感觉 像这样一天又一天地躺在这儿
Sorry about him He doesn't understand what it's like lying there
看人们硬把丑脸帖到你面前
watching people press their ugly faces in on you
你听得懂我的话
Can you hear me
只是 我以前从来没跟蛇讲过话
It's just I've never taliked to a snake before
你
Do you
我是说 你常跟人说话吗
Do you talk to people often
你是从缅甸来的 对吧
You're from Burma aren't you
那儿是不是很美 你想家吗
Was it nice there Do you miss your family
园内孵育样本
我懂了
I see
我也一样 我没见过我的父母
That's me as well I never knew my parents either
妈 爸 快过来 你绝对想不到这只蛇在干嘛
Mummy Dad you won't believe what this snake is doing
谢了
Thanks
别客气
Anytime
蛇
Snake
妈 妈咪 救救我 救命呀
Mum Mummy Help me
宝贝儿子 你是怎么进去的
My darling boy How did you get in there
我的天哪 你是怎么进去的
Who did this How did you get in there
那只是一条蛇 只是一条蛇
Is there a snake Is there a snake
没事的 小甜心
It's all right sweetheart
我们会帮你把这湿冷的衣服脱掉
We'll get you out of these cold clothes
这是怎么回事
What happened
我发誓我真的不知道
I swear I don't know
玻璃忽然消失 就像魔法一样
The glass was there and then it was gone like magic
世上根本就没有魔法
There's no such thing as magic
水蜡树街四号 楼梯下的碗橱 哈利波特先生收
喔 玛吉病了 吃了个怪油螺
Marge is ill Ate a funny whelk
爸 你看 哈利有一封信 嘿 还来 那是我的
Dad look Harry's got a letter It's mine
你的 谁会写信给你啊
Yours Who'd be writing to you
这样就不能再往信箱里投信了
No more mail through this letterbox
祝你上班愉快 亲爱的 我爱你
Have a lovely day at the office dear
快滚
Shoo Go on
星期天真是个好日子
Fine day Sunday
我认为是一星期中最棒的一天
In my opinion best day of the week
这是什么原因 达力
Why is that Dudley
因为星期天不送信
Because there's no post on Sundays
答对了 哈利
Right you are Harry
星期天不送信
No post on Sunday
今天没有讨厌的信 没有
No blasted letters today No sir
没有一封该死的信 完全没有
Not one single bloody letter Not one
没有 没有一封讨厌 可恶的
No sir not one blasted miserable
喔 不
oh no
叫它停下来 拜托
Make it stop please
叫它们停下来 拜托 停下来
Make it stop please Stop it
妈 告诉我 这是怎么一回事
Mummy what's happening
喔 这是什么
What's this
把它给我 把信给我
Give me that Give me that letter
放手
Get off
这是我的信 放开我
They're my letters Let go of me
够了 我们走吧
That's it We're going away
走得远远的 让他们找不到
Far away where they can't find us
爸爸发疯了 是不是
Daddy's gone mad hasn't he
哈利 生日快乐
许个愿吧 哈利
Make a wish Harry
什么人
Who's there
抱歉
Sorry about that
我要你立刻离开 先生 你这是非法侵入民宅
I demand that you leave at once You are breaking and entering
少啰嗦 德思礼 你这大笨蛋
Dry up Dursley you great prune
上回我看到你的时候
I haven't seen you
你还是个婴儿 哈利
Since you was a baby Harry
可是你块头比我想的大多了
You're a bit more along than I expected
而且肚子还这么凸
Particularly in the middle
我又不是哈利
I'm not Harry
我才是
I am
嗯 这才对嘛
Well of course you are
我这儿有个东西要送你
Got something for you
好像不小心被我压到了
Afraid I sat on it
不过味道是不会变的
but I imagine it'll taste fine just the same
全都是我自己烤自己做的唷
Baked it myself words and all
祝哈利生日快乐
谢谢你
Thank you
一辈子就只有这么一次 你现在满十一岁了
It's not every day your young man turns 11 is it
对不起 可是
Excuse me but
你到底是谁呀
who are you
鲁伯 海格 在霍格沃茨担任钥匙管理员与猎场看守人
Rubeus Hagrid Keeper of Keys and Grounds at Hogwarts
你总该知道霍格沃茨吧
Of course you know about Hogwarts
抱歉 不知道
Sorry no
不知道 我的天哪 哈利 没想过你爸妈是怎么学会的
No didn't you ever wonder where your mum and dad learned it all
学会什么
Learned what
你是一个巫师 哈利
You're a wizard Harry
我是一个什么
I'm a what
一个巫师 只要再受点训练 你一定会变成非常厉害的巫师
A wizard a good one I'd wager once you're trained up
不 我想你弄错了
No you've made a mistake
我是说
I mean
我不可能是巫师啊
I can't be a wizard
我是说 我只是
I mean I'm just
哈利 我只是哈利
Harry Just Harry
好吧 哈利
Well Just Harry
你从来没发生过任何怪事吗
Did you ever make anything happen
在你生气害怕的时候 没出现什么搞不懂的怪事吗
Anything you couldn't explain when you were angry or scared
亲爱的波特先生
Dear Mr Potter
我们很荣幸能在此通知你
We are pleased to accept you
你已获准进入 霍格沃茨魔法与巫术学院就读
at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry
我告诉你 我不准他去
He will not be going
我们在收容他那天就发誓要禁止这类的荒唐怪事
We swore we'd put a stop to all this rubbish
你早就知道了
You knew
你们知道却不告诉我
You knew all along and you never told me
当然知道
Of course
想也知道你会是什么德行
We knew How could you not be
看看我那完美的好妹妹
My perfect sister being who she was
她收到信时 爸妈简直乐歪了
My mother and father were so proud the day she got her letter
家里出了个女巫好棒唷
We have a witch in the family Isn't it wonderful
就只有我能看清她的真面目
I was the only one to see her for what she was
她是一个怪胎
A freak
然后她嫁给那个波特 生了你
Then she met that Potter and then she had you
我就知道你会和他们
and I knew you would be the same
一样奇怪 一样不正常
Just as strange just as abnormal
然后了 她就让自己给炸死了 所以我们就只好收留你
And then she got herself blown up and we got landed with you
炸死 你说他们是出车祸死的
Blown up You told me my parents died in a car crash
车祸
A car crash
车祸哪伤得了莉莉 和詹姆波特
A car crash killed Lily and James Potter
我们总得说个理由
We had to say something
这是一种侮辱 一种毁谤
It's an outrage A scandal
他不能去
He'll not be going
你以为像你这种超级大麻瓜 阻止得了他吗
A great Muggle like you is going to stop him
麻瓜
Muggle
就是不会魔法的家伙
Non magic folk
他一出生就列入学生名册了
This boy's had his name down since he were born
他是去世上最棒的 魔法巫术学校
He's going to the finest school of witchcraft and wizardry
而且还有有史以来最棒的校长
He'll be under the finest headmaster Hogwarts has seen
阿不思邓布利多
Albus Dumbledore
休想要我花一文钱 让个疯癫老傻瓜来教他变魔术
I will not pay to have a crackpot old fool teach him magic tricks
不准 在我面前侮辱邓布利多
Never insult Albus Dumbledore in front of me
你可千万别告诉霍格沃茨的人 我会感激你的
I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell anyone at Hogwarts about that
照规定我是不能使用魔法的
I'm not allowed to do magic
好
Okay
进度有点落后了 我们该走了
We're a bit behind schedule Best be off
难不成你还想待在这儿
Unless you'd rather stay of course
所有学生都必须准备
All students must be equipped with
一个标准尺寸的白镴大釜
one standard size 2 pewter cauldron
可自由携带
and may bring if they desire either
一只猫头鹰 猫 或是蟾蜍
An owl a cat or a toad
在伦敦能把东西都买齐吗
Can we find all this in London
只要你知道门路就可以
If you know where to go
是的 那我记得
喔 那个符咒真是太精彩了
啊 海格 老样子对吧
Ah Hagrid The usual I presume
不 谢了 汤姆
No thanks Tom
我正在替霍格沃茨办事
I'm on official Hogwarts business
带小哈利去买学校要用的东西
Just helping Harry buy his school supplies
上帝保佑我
Bless my soul
他是哈利波特
It's Harry Potter
欢迎回来 波特先生
Welcome back Mr Potter
欢迎回来
Welcome back
我是桃莉 波特先生 真不敢相信我终于见到你了
Doris Crockford Mr Potter I can't believe I'm meeting you at last
哈利波特
Harry Potter
见到你真说不出有多高兴
Can't tell you how pleased I am to meet you
你好 教授 刚才没看到你
Hello professor I didn't see you
哈利 这位是奇洛教授 霍格沃茨的黑魔法防御术老师
Harry This's Professor Quirrell will be your Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher
喔 真高兴见到你
Oh nice to meet you
这门课迷人得很
Fearfully fascinating subject
但你已经不用学了 对吧 波特
Not that you need it eh Potter
现在得上路了 好多东西要买
Yes well must be going now Lots to buy
再见
Goodbye
瞧 哈利 你有名得很
See Harry You're famous
但我为什么会出名了 海格
But why am I famous Hagrid
那些人为什么全都认识我
All those people how is it they know who I am
我不知道这事由我来告诉你 究竟合不合适 哈利
I'm not sure I'm the right person to tell you that Harry
欢迎来到斜角巷 哈利
Welcome Harry to Diagon Alley
这儿可以买到羽毛笔和墨水
Here you get your quills and ink
那边是卖各式各样的魔法玩意 买些龙爪怎么样
Over there all your bits and bobs for doing wizardry
世界级的比赛用飞天扫帚
It's a world class racing broom
哇 快看 最新型的光轮两千
Look at it The new Nimbus 2000
目前最快的型号
It's the fastest model yet
光轮两千
但是 我哪买得起这些东西
But how am I to pay for all this
我连一毛钱也没有
I haven't any money
你的钱在那里 哈利
There's your money Harry
古灵阁 巫师银行
Gringotts the wizard bank
那可算是世上最安全的地方
Ain't no safer place not one
除了霍格沃茨以外
Except perhaps Hogwarts
海格 那是什么怪物呀
Hagrid what exactly are these things
那就是妖精啊 哈利
They're goblins  Harry
妖精聪明得很 但可不太友善
Clever as they come but not the most friendly of beasts
最好是紧跟在我身边
Best stay close
哈利波特先生想要提钱
Mr Harry Potter wishes to make a withdrawal
哈利波特先生有带钥匙吗
And does Mr Harry Potter have his key
喔 等等 就在身上
Wait a minute Got it here somewhere
小鬼难缠
Ha There's the little devil
喔 还有另一件事
And there's something else as well
这是邓布利多教授交给我的
Professor Dumbledore gave me this
最高机密
就是那个金库里的那个东西
It's about You Know What in vault you know which
好的
Very well
六百八十七号地下金库
Vault 687
请把灯给我
Lamp please
钥匙
Key please
你以为你爸妈 什么也没留给你
Did you think your parents would leave you with nothing
七百十三号地下金库
Vault 713
里面放了什么东西 海格
What's in there Hagrid
这我可不能告诉你 哈利
Can't tell you Harry
那是霍格沃茨的最高机密
Hogwarts business Very secret
退后
Stand back
最好别跟任何人提起这回事
Best not to mention this to anyone
我还需要一根魔杖
I still need a wand
魔杖 好 去奥利凡德吧
A wand You want OIlivanders
那是最棒的地方
There ain't no place better
你先自己进去看看好吗
Run along there and wait
我还有件事要办 去去就来
I got one more thing to do Won't be long
你好
Hello
我才在想什么时候会见到你
I wondered when I'd be seeing you
波特先生
Mr Potter
那好像是昨天才发生的事
It seems only yesterday
你父母上这儿来买第一根魔杖
that your mother and father were in here buying their first wands
我们试试这个
Here we are
好 挥挥看吧
Give it a wave
显然不行
Apparently not
也许
Perhaps
这个可以
this
不行 不行 绝对不行
No no definitely not
没关系
No matter
我想应该是它
I wonder
真稀奇
Curious
真的是非常稀奇
Very curious
对不起 你为什么觉得稀奇
Sorry but what's curious
我记得我卖出的每一根魔杖
I remember every wand I've ever sold
波特先生
Mr Potter
凑巧的是
It so happens that the phoenix
给了你魔杖一根尾羽的 那只凤凰另外还有一根尾羽给了
whose tail feather resides in your wand gave another feather
另外一根魔杖
Just one other
而稀奇的是 你注定就要使用这根魔杖
It is curious that you should be destined for this wand
因另一根魔杖的主人 在你额头留下了那道疤痕
when its brother gave you that scar
那根魔杖的主人是谁
And who owned that wand
喔 他的名字我们不能说
We do not speak his name
是魔杖选择巫师 波特先生
The wand chooses the wizard Mr Potter
原因向来无法理解
It's not always clear why
但我想这次很清楚
But I think it is clear
你未来会有了不起的成就
that we can expect great things from you
不管怎么说
After all
那个不能说出名字的人
He Who Must Not Be Named
做了些很了不起的事
Did great things
虽然可怕
Terrible
但还是很了不起
Yes but great
哈利 哈利
Harry Harry
生日快乐
Happy birthday
喔 哇
oh
你没事吧 怎么都不吭声了
You all right Harry You seem very quiet
是他杀了我的父母 对不对
He killed my parents didn't he
就是那个害我留下这道疤的人
The one who gave me this
你知道的 海格
You know Hagrid
你一定知道
I know you do
你得先了解一件事 哈利
First and understand this Harry
因为这非常重要
Because it's very important
巫师并不一定都是好人
Not all wizards are good
有些巫师会变坏
Some of them go bad
几年前
A few years ago
有个巫师简直坏到骨子里去了
there was a wizard who went as bad as you can go
他的名字叫佛
His name was V
还是你用写的好了
Maybe if you wrote it down
不行 这字我不会拼
No I can't spell it
好吧 佛地魔 佛地魔
All right Voldemort Voldemort
那真是一段可怕的日子 哈利
It was dark times Harry
佛地魔那时聚集了一批爪牙
Voldemort started to gather some followers
说动他们投靠黑暗势力
Brought them over to the Dark Side
反抗他的人全都被杀光
Anyone that stood up to him ended up dead
你爸妈勇敢跟他对抗
Your parents fought against him
但只要是他决定要杀的人 没一个能逃过他的毒手
But nobody lived once he decided to kill them
没有 一个也没有
Nobody not one
只有你例外
Except you
我 佛地魔想杀我
Me Voldemort tried to kill me
没错 你额头上的疤很不寻常 哈利
Yes That ain't no ordinary cut on your forehead Harry
只有诅咒才会留下那样的痕迹 而且是个邪恶的诅咒
A mark like that only comes from being touched by a curse an evil curse
那佛 那个人后来怎么样
What happened to V  To You Know Who
这个嘛 有人说他死了
Well some say he died
但依我看是胡说八道
Codswallop in my opinion
不 我想他还躲在某个地方
Nope I reckon he's out there still
虚弱得无法采取行动
too tired to carry on
但有件事倒是可以确定
But one thing's certain
你那晚让他栽了个大跟斗
Something about you stumped him that night
所以你才会这么有名
That's why you're famous
大家才会全都认识你
That's why everybody knows your name
你可是唯一活下来的男孩
You're the boy who lived
你们在看什么
What are you looking at
哎呀 现在几点啦
Blimey is that the time
对不起 哈利 我得走了
I'm gonna have to leave you
邓布利多等着要拿他的
Dumbledore will be wanting his
好了 他等着要见我
Well he'll be wanting to see me
你的火车再十分钟就要开了
Your train leaves in 10 minutes
这是你的车票
Here's your ticket
把车票收好 这很重要
Stick to your ticket that's very important
九又四分之三月台
Platform 93/4
但是 海格 这一定弄错了
But Hagrid there must be a mistake
上面写九又四分之三月台
This says platform 93/4
哪有这种月台呀
There's no such thing is there
抱歉
Sorry
对不起 对不起
Excuse me Excuse me
从左边通道穿过去
On your left
对不起 先生
Excuse me sir
九又四分之三月台在哪儿
Can you tell me where I might find platform 93/4
九又四分之三月台
platform 93/4
你故意装傻整我开心吗
Think you're being funny do you
每年都一样 挤满了麻瓜 这是当然的 走吧
It's the same every year packed with Muggles
麻瓜 九又四分之三月台
Muggles Platform 93/4 this way
好 派西 你先走
All right Percy you first
弗雷 你下一个
Fred you next
他不是弗雷 我才是
He's not Fred I am
你还好意思自称母亲嘛
You call yourself our mother
喔 对不起 乔治
I'm sorry George
开玩笑的啦 我是弗雷
I'm only joking I am Fred
对不起
Excuse me
能 能不能请你告诉我
Could you tell me
要怎样
how to
什么 怎样去月台吗
How to get onto the platform
放心 没问题的 亲爱的
Not to worry dear
荣恩也是第一次去霍格沃茨
It's Ron's first time to Hogwarts as well
现在你只要往第九和第十月台中间那道墙直接走过去就行了
All you do is walk straight at the wall between platforms 9 and 10
要是紧张的话 最好用小跑步
Best to run if you're nervous
祝你好运
Good luck
九又四分之三月台 霍格沃茨特快车
对不起
Excuse me
我可以坐吗 其它车厢都满了
Do you mind Everywhere else is full
坐啊
Not at all
对了 我叫荣恩 荣恩韦斯莱
I'm Ron by the way Ron Weasley
我叫哈利 哈利波特
I'm Harry Harry Potter
所以 所以那是真的了
So it's true
我是说 你真的有
I mean do you really have the
有什么
The what
那道疤
The scar
喔 对啊
Oh yes
真炫
Wicked
要不要买点儿东西吃呀
Anything off the trolley dears
不 谢了 我自己有带吃的
No thanks I'm all set
我全部都要
We'll take the lot
柏蒂全口味豆
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans
这表示所有口味都有
They mean every flavor
有巧克力和薄荷口味 也有
There's chocolate and peppermint and also
菠菜 肝脏 还有牛肚
spinach liver and tripe
乔治有次还吃到鼻涕口味
George sweared he got a booger flavored one once
这该不会是真的青蛙吧
Are they real frogs
只是施了个符咒啦
It's a spell
而且这还可以让你搜集卡片
You want the cards
每包附一张名巫师或女巫卡片
Each pack's got a famous witch or wizard
已经收集大约五百张了
I've got about 500 meself
小心
Watch it
喔 运气真背
That's rotten luck
它们只有一开始那下跳得最好
They've only got one good jump in them
我有邓布利多
I've got Dumbledore
邓布利多我已经有了 足足有六张
I've got Dumbledore I got about six of him
嘿 他不见了
Hey he's gone
你不能要他整天都待在那儿吧
You can't expect him to hang around all day can you
对了 这是斑斑
This is Scabbers
他很可怜 对不对
Pathetic isn't he
还好啦
A little
弗雷教了我一个咒语 可以把它变成黄色 要看吗
Fred gave me a spell to turn him yellow Want to see
好啊
Yeah
阳
Sun
有没有人看到一只蟾蜍
Has anyone seen a toad
奈威的蟾蜍不见了
A boy named Neville's lost one
没有
No
喔 你在施魔法吗
Oh are you doing magic
让我们瞧一瞧吧
Let's see then
阳光 雏菊 甜奶油
Sunshine daisies butter mellow
将这只又胖又笨老鼠变成黄色
Turn this stupid fat rat yellow
你确定这是真的咒语吗
Are you sure that's a real spell
显然不是很有用 对不对
Well it's not very good is it
我也只试过几个简单的咒语
I've only tried a few simple ones myself
但每次都非常成功
but they've all worked for me
比方说
For example:
欧卡拉斯雷培洛
Oculus Reparo
是不是好了
That's better isn't it
我的天哪 你是哈利波特
Holy cricket you're Harry Potter
我叫赫敏格兰杰
I'm Hermione Granger
那你是
And you are
我叫荣恩韦斯莱
I'm Ron Weasley
幸会
Pleasure
你们两个最好赶快换上长袍
You two better change into robes
我们大概快要到了
I expect we'll be arriving soon
你鼻子上黑黑的 知道吗
You've got dirt on your nose Did you know
就在这
Just there
好 一年级新生
Right then First years
请跟我来
This way please
快呀 一年级新生 别害羞
Come on first years don't be shy
走呀 快点 走呀
Come on now hurry up
你好 哈利
Hello Harry
嘿 海格
Hi Hagrid
好 走这儿上船
Right then This way to the boats
快 跟我来
Come on now follow me
真炫
Wicked
欢迎来到霍格沃茨
Welcome to Hogwarts
待会儿你们就要走进这扇门跟其它同学齐聚一堂
Shortly you'll pass through these doors and join your classmates
但在你们到餐厅入席之前必须先替你们分派学院
But before you take your seats you must be sorted into your houses
学院有葛来分多 赫夫帕夫
They are Gryffindor Hufflepuff
雷文克劳 还有史莱哲林
Ravenclaw and Slytherin
在你们就学期间 学院就像是你们的家一样
While you're here your house will be like your family
你们表现出色会替学院加分
Your triumphs will earn you points
而违规则会使学院被扣分
Any rule breaking and you will lose points
学年结束时 积分最高的学院将会获得学院杯冠军
At the end of the year the house with the most points wins the house cup
吹宝
Trevor
对不起
Sorry
分类仪式马上就要开始了
The Sorting Ceremony will begin momentarily
那是真的了火车上的传闻果真没错
It's true then what they're saying on the train
哈利波特到霍格沃茨来了
Harry Potter has come to Hogwarts
哈利波特
Harry Potter
这是克拉和高尔 我叫马尔福
This is Crabbe and Goyle And I'm Malfoy
德拉科 马尔福
Draco Malfoy
觉得我名字很好笑是不是
Think my name's funny do you
我不用问就知道你是谁
I've no need to ask yours
红头发 旧长袍
Red hair and a hand me down robe
你想必是韦斯莱家的人
You must be a Weasley
你马上就会发现 某些巫师家庭比别人高级些
You'll find out some wizarding families are better than others
没人会想跟差劲家伙交朋友
You don't want to go making friends with the wrong sort
这方面我可以帮你
I can help you there
我可以看得出是谁比较差劲 谢了
I think I can tell the wrong sort for myself thanks
一切准备就绪 请跟我来吧
We're ready for you now Follow me
他们对天花板施了魔法
The ceiling isn't real
让它看起来像是夜晚的天空
It's bewitched to look like the night sky
我在 霍格沃茨 一段历史  这本书上读到过
I read about it in Hogwarts A History
请在这儿等一下
Will you wait along here please
听着 在我们开始之前
Now before we begin
邓布利多教授要先说几句话
Professor Dumbledore would like to say a few words
我想向大家宣布 新学期一些必须注意事项
I have a few start of term notices I wish to announce
一年级新生注意了
The first years please note
黑森林绝对禁止学生进入
that the Dark Forest is strictly forbidden to all students
另外 管理员飞七先生要我提醒各位
Also our caretaker Mr Filch has asked me to remind you
不可踏进三楼右手边走廊
that the third floor corridor is out of bounds
除非你想七窍流血 痛苦惨死
to everyone who does not wish to die a most painful death
谢谢大家
Thank you
当我叫到你的名字你就走到前面来
When I call your name you will come forth
我会把分类帽戴到你头上
I shall place the Sorting Hat on your head
替你分派学院
and you will be sorted into your houses
赫敏格兰杰
Hermione Granger
喔 不
Oh no
好 放轻松
Okay relax
我告诉你 那家伙头脑有问题
Mental that one I'm telling you
啊 很好 嗯 好
Right then Right
决定了
Okay
葛来分多
Gryffindor
德拉科 马尔福
Draco Malfoy
史莱哲林
Slytherin
所有变坏的巫师和女巫全都是史莱哲林出身的
Every wizard who went bad was in Slytherin
苏珊波恩
Susan Bones
哈利 怎么了
Harry what is it
没什么 没什么 我没事
Nothing Nothing I'm fine
让我想想
Let's see
我知道了
I know
赫夫帕夫
Hufflepuff
荣恩 韦斯莱
Ronald Weasley
又来一个韦斯莱 不用想也知道该把你分到
Another Weasley I know just what to do with you
葛来分多
Gryffindor
哈利波特
Harry Potter
很困难 非常困难
Difficult very difficult
勇气很足够 心地也不坏
Plenty of courage I see Not a bad mind either
也很有才华 没错
There's talent oh yes
和一股急着想证明自己的欲望
And a thirst to prove yourself
但我该把你分到哪了
But where to put you
不要史莱哲林 不要史莱哲林
Not Slytherin not Slytherin
不要史莱哲林 你确定
Not Slytherin eh Are you sure
你会有了不起的成就 你脑袋里该有的样样不缺
You could be great you know It's all here in your head
而史莱哲林 可以帮助你登上巅峰 这一点是毫无疑问的
And Slytherin will help you on the way to greatness no doubt about that
不要 好吧 既然你这么确定
No Well if you're sure
那就最好是去
Better be
葛来分多
Gryffindor
请大家注意
Your attention please
宴会开始
Let the feast begin
我是一半一半
I'm half and half
我爸是麻瓜 我妈是女巫
Me dad's a Muggle Mum's a witch
他发现时可真是吓坏了
Bit of a nasty shock for him when he found out
告诉我 派西 那个在跟奇洛说话的人是谁
Percy who's that teacher talking to Professor Quirrell
喔 那是斯内普教授 史莱哲林的学院导师
Professor Snape head of Slytherin house
他教什么科目
What's he teach
魔药学
Potions
但他最感兴趣的是 黑魔法防御术
But he fancies the Dark Arts
他早就想接下奇洛的工作了
He's been after Quirrell's job for years
你好 欢迎加入葛来分多
Hello How are you Welcome to Gryffindor
看 那是血腥男爵
It's the Bloody Baron
你好 尼古拉斯爵士
Hello Sir Nicholas
暑假过得还愉快吗
Have a nice summer
惨哪 我想参加无头骑士狩猎 但是又再度遭到拒绝
Dismal Once again my request to join the Headless Hunt has been denied
我知道你是谁
I know you
你是差点没头的尼克
You're Nearly Headless Nick
我希望你能叫我尼古拉斯爵士
I prefer Sir Nicholas if you don't mind
差点没头
Nearly headless
你是怎么个差点没头法
How can you be nearly headless
就像这样
Like this
葛来分多学生请跟我走
Gryffindors follow me please
快跟上啊 谢谢
Keep up Thank you
雷文克劳学生跟我走
Ravenclaw follow me
往这边走
This way
这是去寝室最快的一条路
This is the most direct path to the dormitories
小心楼梯 它们喜欢变来变去
Keep an eye on the staircases They like to change
请大家跟好 跟我来
Keep up please and follow me
现在走快点 快啊
Quickly now come on Come on
西莫 那幅画在动
That picture's moving
你看那幅画 哈利 我想她是看上你了
Look at that one I think she fancies you
喔 看 快看
Look
那女的是谁
Who's that girl
欢迎来到霍格沃茨
Welcome to Hogwarts
那是谁啊
Who's that
通关密语
Password
龙渣
Caput Draconis
大家跟我走
Follow me
快跟上 快
everyone Keep up Quickly come on
大家先在这儿集合
Gather around here
欢迎来到葛来分多交谊厅
Welcome to the Gryffindor common room
男生寝室在楼上左边 女生寝室在右边
Boys' dormitory is upstairs to the left Girls the same on your right
行李都已经替你们送上去了
Your belongings have already been brought up
唷 及时赶上
Made it
要是迟到的话 麦格教授的脸不知道会有多难看
Can you imagine the look on old McGonagall's face if we were late
真是太厉害了
That was bloody brilliant
喔 谢谢你的评论 韦斯莱先生
Thank you for that assessment Mr Weasley
说不定我变些别的还比较有用 把你或波特先生变成一只表
It'd be better if I transfigured Mr Potter and you into a watch
这样你们至少有个人不会迟到
Then one of you might be on time
我们迷路了
We got lost
所以该变张地图了
Then perhaps a map
找位子坐总不必用到地图吧
I trust you don't need one to find your seats
这门课不需要你傻呼呼挥魔杖或是叽哩咕噜瞎念咒
There will be no foolish wand waving or silly incantations in this class
所以了
As such
我并不期待大多数人能理解
I don't expect many of you to appreciate
制魔药的精密科学与正确技术
the subtle science and exact art that is potion making
不过了 那些出类拔萃
However for those select few
拥有特殊天赋的少数人
who possess the predisposition
我可以教你们如何混乱心智
I can teach you how to bewitch the mind
和迷惑感官
And ensnare the senses
我可以教你们如何赢取名声 熬煮荣耀
I can tell you how to bottle fame
甚至阻止死亡
brew glory and even put a stopper in death
另外
Then again
也许你们有些人在入学时
Maybe some of you have come to Hogwarts in possession of abilities
就已具有非凡的能力让你目空一切
So formidable that you feel confident enough
懒得注意听讲
To not pay attention
波特先生
Mr Potter
我们这儿的新名人
Our new celebrity
我若把水仙球根粉倒入苦艾汁 会产生什么样的效果
What would I get if I added root of asphodel to an infusion of wormwood
你不知道
You don't know
好 我们再试一次
Let's try again
若是我要你拿一块毛粪石给我 你要到哪找
Where would you look if I asked you to find a bezoar
我不知道 先生
I don't know sir
那附子和牛扁有什么不同
What is the difference between monkshood and wolfsbane
我不知道 先生
I don't know sir
可怜哪
Pity
名气显然并不能代表一切
Clearly fame isn't everything
是不是啊 波特先生
Is it Mr Potter
兔子眼 琴炫幽幽 快将清水变甜酒
Eye of rabbit harp string hum Turn this water into rum
兔子眼 琴炫幽幽
Eye of rabbit
西莫干嘛对那杯水念个不停
What's Seamus trying to do to the water
想把它变成甜酒 他昨天把水变成了淡茶 在他
Turn it to rum Actually managed a weak tea yesterday before
啊 信来了
Mail's here
这可不可以借我看看
Can I borrow this
谢了
Thanks
你看 奈威收到了一个记忆球
Look Neville's got a Remembrall
这我在书上看过
I've read about those
烟要是变红的话就表示你忘了某件事情
The smoke turns red when you've forgotten something
问题是
The problem is
我根本就不记得我忘了什么啊
I can't remember what I've forgotten
嘿 荣恩 有人非法闯入古灵阁
Ron Somebody broke into Gringotts Listen
你看 据说是某位不知名巫师 或女巫所策划的行动
Believed to be the work of Dark wizards or witches
古灵阁妖精虽承认被侵入 但却否认损失任何物品
Gringotts goblins acknowledge the breach but insist nothing was taken
出事的713号地下金库 事实上已在当日稍早 被提领一空
The vault in question number 713 had been emptied earlier that same day
奇怪了
That's odd
那就是海格带我去的金库
That's the vault Hagrid and I went to
同学们午安
Good afternoon class
午安 霍琦夫人
Good afternoon Madam Hooch
午安 阿曼达 午安
Good afternoon Amanda Good afternoon
欢迎大家来上第一堂飞行课
Welcome to your first flying lesson
好了 你们还在琢磨什么
What are you waiting for
每个人都站到自己扫帚左边
Step up to your broomstick
快呀 快点 把右手伸到扫帚上方 说 上来
Come on now hurry up Stick your hand over the broom and say Up
上来
Up
上来 上来
Up Up
要带点感情
With feeling
上来 上来
Up Up
上来
Up
闭嘴 哈利
Shut up Harry
听好 抓住扫帚以后 就请你们骑上去
Now once you've got hold of your broom I want you to mount it
抓紧一点 免得从后面滑下来
Grip it tight You don't wanna be sliding off the end
我一吹口哨 你们大家就用力往上跳
When I blow my whistle I want you to kick off from the ground hard
尽量让扫帚保持稳定 在空中飞一会儿
Keep your broom steady hover for a moment
然后身子微往前倾轻轻飞回地面
then lean forward slightly and touch back down
听我的口哨 三 二
On my whistle Three two
隆巴顿先生
Mr Longbottom
快下来
Down
奈威
Neville
隆巴顿先生 下去 下去
Mr Longbottom Down down
奈威
Neville
立刻给我下来
Come back down this instant
隆巴顿先生
Mr Longbottom
大家全都让开
Everyone out of the way
他没事吧
Is he all right
喔 喔 亲爱的 手腕断了 可怜的孩子 好了 站起来吧
Oh dear it's a broken wrist Poor boy Come on now up you get
在我带这孩子去医护室时 全都给我乖乖站好不准乱飞
Keep your feet on the ground while I take him to the hospital wing
听到没有 要是让我看到有人飞上天空
Understand If I see a single broom in the air
那他还来不及见识到魁地奇就得给我滚出霍格沃茨
The one riding it will be expelled before they can say Quidditch
你们看到他那张蠢脸了吗
Did you see his face
那个大胖子 要是有捏一捏记忆球就会记得摔跤时该屁股先着地
If he had squeezed this he'd have remembered to fall on his arse
把它交出来 马尔福
Give it here Malfoy
不 我要把它藏在某个地方 让隆巴顿玩玩寻宝游戏
No I'll leave it somewhere for Longbottom to find
放在屋顶上怎么样啊
How about on the roof
怎么了 波特 拿不到是吧
What's the matter Potter Bit beyond your reach
哈利 不行
Harry no way
你刚才也听到霍琦夫人说的话
You heard what Madam Hooch said
何况你根本就不会飞嘛
Besides you don't know how to fly
真是个大白痴
What an idiot
给我 马尔福 不然我就把你踢下扫帚
Give it here or I'll knock you off your broom
是吗
Is that so
那你就来拿吧
Have it your way then
太棒了 哈利
Nice going Harry
干得好 哈利
That was wicked Harry
真炫 哈利
Wicked Harry
哈利波特
Harry Potter
跟我来
Follow me
在这儿等着
You wait here
对不起 奇洛教授
Professor Quirrell excuse me
能不能把伍德借给我一下
Could I borrow Wood for a moment
嗯 当然可以
Yes of course
波特 这位是奥利佛伍德
Potter this is Oliver Wood
伍德 我替你找到了搜捕手
Wood I have found you a Seeker
听说了吗
Have you heard
葛来分多的新搜捕手 是哈利波特
Harry Potter's the new Gryffindor Seeker
我早就看出他会有出色的表现
I always knew he'd do well
搜捕手
Seeker
但学院代表队 从不收一年级新生
But first years never make the house teams
你铁定是魁地奇球队 一百年来最年轻的代表队员
You must be the youngest player in A century
这是麦格教授告诉我的
McGonagall says
干得好 哈利 伍德刚才告诉我们了
Well done Harry Wood's just told us
弗雷和乔治也是队员
Fred and George are on the team Beaters
他们是打击手 我们的任务是尽量别让你被打得太惨
Our job is to make sure you don't get bloodied up too bad
但我们自然不敢担保 魁地奇比赛粗暴得很
Can't make any promises Rough game Quidditch
野蛮得很 但很久没死人了
But no one's died in years
偶尔会有人消失
Someone vanishes occasionally
不过一 两个月就会再出现
But they'll turn up in a month or two
喔 走啊 哈利 魁地奇很刺激它是世上最棒的比赛 你也会表现得很棒的
Go on Harry Quidditch is great Best game there is and you'll be great too
可是我从来就没打过魁地奇 要是出丑怎么办
I've never played What if I make a fool of myself
你不会出丑的啦 你可是家学渊源的搜捕手
You won't make a fool of yourself It's in your blood
哈利 你没告诉我 你父亲也是搜捕手
Harry you never told me your father was a Seeker too
我也不知道
I didn't know
我告诉你 我觉得这很恐怖
I'm telling you it's spooky
她知道的事居然比你还多
She knows more about you than you do
谁知道的都会比他多
Who doesn't
怎么了
What's happening
楼梯会变来变去 记得吗
The staircases change remember
走这边
Let's go this way
免得楼梯又开始乱动
Before the staircase moves again
这儿好像不是我们该来的地方
Does anybody feel like we shouldn't be here
我们不能到这里来呀
We're not supposed to be here
这是三楼 这是禁区
This is the third floor It's forbidden
我们走吧
Let's go
是飞七的猫
It's Filch's cat
快跑
Run
快 躲到那扇门后面
Quick let's hide through that door
门锁上了
It's locked
这下我们真的完了
We're done for
喔 让开
Move over
阿洛哈呣啦
Alohomora
快进去
Get in
阿洛哈呣啦
Alohomora
标准咒语 第七章
Standard Book of Spells chapter seven
这儿有人吗 小甜心
Anyone here my sweet
走吧
Come on
飞七走了
Filch is gone
他大概以为这扇门是锁上的
He thinks this door's locked
本来就是锁上的 门锁上是有原因的
It was locked And for good reason
他们这些人到底是什么意思 竟然把那种东西关在学校
What are they doing keeping a thing like that locked up in a school
你们不会用眼睛看吗 没看到它站在什么东西上面
Didn't you see what it was standing on
我没注意到它的脚 它的头就够我看花眼了
I wasn't looking at its feet I was preoccupied with its heads
你说不定没注意到 它有三个头
Or maybe you didn't notice There were three
它站在一扇活板门上
It was standing on a trap door
这代表它是有用处的
It wasn't there by accident
它在看守某个东西
It's guarding something
看守某个东西
Guarding something
没错
That's right
你们不介意的话 我要去睡了
Now if you two don't mind I'm going to bed
免得你们又想出什么鬼主意来害我们送命
Before you come up with another idea to get us killed
或是更糟 被学校开除
Or worse expelled
她还真分不清事情的轻重
She needs to sort out her priorities
魁地奇的规则还蛮好懂的
Quidditch is easy to understand
每队有七名球员
Each team has seven players
三个追踪手 两个打击手
Three Chasers two Beaters
还有看守手和搜捕手
One keeper and a Seeker
你就是搜捕手
That's you
总共有三种球
There are three kinds of balls
这叫做快浮
This one's called the Quaffle
追踪手把快浮传来传去设法把它射进那三个球框
The Chasers handle the Quaffle and try to put it through one of those hoops
看守手就是我 负责看守球框
The Keeper that's me defends the hoops
还跟得上吗
With me so far
可以
I think so
那些是什么
What are those
你最好握住这个
You better take this
小心 它飞回来了
Careful now it's coming back
嗯 不错嘛 波特 你也可成为优秀的打击手
Not bad Potter You'd make a fair Beater
那是什么东西
What was that
搏格
Bludger
难缠的小东西
Nasty little buggers
但你是一名搜捕手
But you are a Seeker
你只要担心这个就行了
The only thing I want you to worry about is this
金探子
The Golden Snitch
我喜欢这个球
I like this ball You like it now
啊 你喜欢它了等着瞧吧 它速度奇快而且神出鬼没
Just wait It's wicked fast and damn near impossible to see
那我要做什么
What do I do with it
赶在别队搜捕手之前抓住它
You catch it Before the other team's Seeker
你一抓到它 比赛就会结束
You catch this the game's over
你一抓到它 波特
You catch this Potter
我们就赢了
And we win
飘浮是巫师最基本的技巧之一
One of a wizard's most rudimentary skills is levitation
这种魔法可以让物体飞起来
Or the ability to make objects fly
大家都拿到羽毛了吗
Do you have your feathers
很好
Good
现在
Now
别忘了我们练习过的手腕动作
Don't forget the nice wrist movement we've been practicing
挥和弹 大家一起念
The swish and flick Everyone
挥和弹 很好 还有发音也很重要
The swish and flick Good Oh and enunciate
温咖癫啦唯啊萨 大家开始练习吧
Wingardium Leviosa Off you go then
温咖癫啦唯啊萨
Wingardium Leviosa
停下来
No stop stop stop
你会把别人眼睛给戳瞎的
You're going to take someone's eye out
而且你的发音不正确
Besides you're saying it wrong
应该要强调 啊 而不是 萨
It's Leviosa not Leviosar
既然你这么聪明 干脆你自己来试试看
You do it then if you're so clever Go on go on
温咖癫啦唯啊萨
Wingardium Leviosa
表现得很好 大家快看 格兰杰小姐成功了
Well done See here everyone Miss Granger's done it
好极了
Splendid
温咖癫啦唯啊萨
Wingardium Leviosa
表现得很好
Well done dear
麻烦再给我们一根羽毛 教授
I think we're going to need another feather over here Professor
应该要强调 啊 而不是 萨
It's Leviosa not Leviosar
她实在是太讨人厌了
She's a nightmare honestly
难怪连一个朋友也没有
No wonder she hasn't got any friends
好像被她听见了
I think she heard you
赫敏了
Where's Hermione
芭蒂说她把自己 关在女生厕所里
Parvati said she wouldn't come out of the bathroom
躲在那里哭了一整个下午
She said that she'd been in there all afternoon crying
山怪在地牢里
Troll in the dungeon
地牢里有山怪
我想应该通报你一声
Thought you ought to know
安静
Silence
请大家不要慌张
Everyone will please not panic
现在
Now
各位级长把自己学院的学生带回寝室
prefects will lead their house back to the dormitories
老师们跟我一起去地牢
Teachers will follow me to the dungeons
葛来分多的学生 请跟上来 保持警戒
Gryffindors keep up please and stay alert
山怪是怎么进来的
How could a troll get in
他不是自己进来的 山怪很笨 可能是有人在恶作剧
Not on its own Trolls are really stupid Probably people playing jokes
怎么啦
What
赫敏还不知道山怪的事
Hermione She doesn't know
山怪好像离开地牢了
I think the troll's left the dungeon
他朝女生厕所走过去了
It's going into the girls' bathroom
赫敏 快跑啊
Hermione move
救命啊
Help
嘿 笨蛋
Hey pea brain
救命啊
Help
快想办法
Do something
什么办法
What
什么办法都行
Anything
快点
Hurry up
挥和弹
Swish and flick
温咖癫啦唯啊萨
Wingardium Leviosa
酷毙了
Cool
他是不是死掉了
Is it dead
好像还没死 只是昏倒而已
I don't think so Just knocked out
山怪鼻屎
Troll boogers
我的天啊 请你们两位解释一下
Oh my goodness Explain yourselves both of you
都是我不好 麦格教授
Well what it is It's my fault Professor McGonagall
什么
What
格兰杰小姐
Miss Granger
我跑去找山怪了
I went looking for the troll
我在书上读过山怪的事 自以为对付得了他
I thought I could handle it
但我错了
But I was wrong
要不是哈利和荣恩及时救了我
If Harry and Ron hadn't come and found me
我搞不好就没命了
I'd probably be dead
既然如此 你这种行为实在是太愚蠢了
Be that as it may it was an extremely foolish thing to do
我本来以为你会理智一点 我对你很失望
I expected more rational behavior and am very disappointed in you
葛来分多要被扣掉五分
Five points will be taken from Gryffindor
因为你严重缺乏判断力
For your serious lack of judgment
至于你们两位
As for you two gentlemen
你们的运气实在是太好了
I just hope you realize how fortunate you are
很少新生可以制伏成年山怪
Not many first year students could take on a troll
而且还能活着回来
And live to tell the tale
五分
Five points
你们两位各加五分
Will be awarded to each of you
只因为你们歪打正着
For sheer dumb luck
你们还是快走吧
Perhaps you ought to go
山怪可能会醒过来
It might wake up
吃点吐司吧 朋友
Take a bit of toast mate Go on
荣恩说得对 哈利
Ron's right Harry
你今天需要足够的体力
You'll need your strength today
我不饿
I'm not hungry
祝你好运 波特
Good luck today Potter
话又说回来 既然你制伏了山怪
You've proven yourself against a troll
魁地奇比赛应该难不倒你
A game of Quidditch should be easy work
就算对手是史莱哲林也无妨
Even if it is against Slytherin
难怪会有血
That explains the blood
血 我猜昨晚是斯内普
Blood Last night I'm guessing Snape
把山怪放进来声东击西
Let the troll in as a diversion
好趁机通过三头巨犬那一关
So he could get past that dog
结果却被咬了
But he got bit that's why he's limping
所以走路才会一跛一跛的 他干嘛要接近那只巨犬
But why would anyone go near that dog
他说那是霍格沃茨的最高机密
Said it was Hogwarts business very secret
你的意思是
You're saying
那是三头巨犬在看守的东西
That's what the dog's guarding
斯内普想把它偷到手
That's what Snape wants
这么早就收到邮包啊
Bit early for mail isn't it
从来没人寄邮包给我
But I never get mail
拆开来看看
Let's open it
是一把扫帚
It's a broomstick
那不是普通的扫帚
That's not just a broomstick
那是光轮两千
It's a Nimbus 2000
到底是谁
But who
你会怕吗 哈利
Scared Harry
有一点
A little
没关系
It's all right
我第一次上场之前也有点怕
I felt the same way before my first game
结果了
What happened
我不太记得了
I don't really remember
没两分钟就被搏格打到头
I took a Bludger to the head two minutes in
在医院昏迷一个星期才醒来
Woke up in hospital a week later
欢迎各位观赏霍格沃茨
Welcome to Hogwarts'
本季的第一场魁地奇比赛
First Quidditch game of the season
今天是史莱哲林对战葛来分多
Today's game Slytherin versus Gryffindor
葛来分多
Gryffindor
选手们各就各位
The players take their positions
霍琦夫人上场准备开球
As Madam Hooch steps onto the field to begin the game
希望这会是场光明正大的比赛
Now I want a nice clean game
大家都要遵守规则
From all of you
搏格都飞起来了 接着是金探子
The Bludgers are up followed by the Golden Snitch
记住 抢到金探子可以得到150分
Remember the Snitch is worth 150 points
搜捕手一抢到金探子 比赛就宣告结束
The Seeker who catches the Snitch ends the game
放出快浮 比赛开始
The Quaffle is released and the game begins
莉娜得分了
Angelina Johnson scores
葛来分多得了十分
Ten points for Gryffindor
好
Yes
干得好
Well done
快浮落入史莱哲林手中 赖里把搏格传给队长马科福林
Slytherin takes the Quaffle Bletchley passes to Captain Marcus Flint
好
Yes
葛来分多又得了十分
Another ten points to Gryffindor
给我
Give me that
守住那边
Take that side
哈利的扫帚怎么啦
What's going on with Harry's broomstick
是斯内普 他在对扫帚下咒
It's Snape He's jinxing the broom
对扫帚下咒 我们该怎么办
Jinxing the broom What do we do
交给我吧
Leave it to me
快点啊 赫敏
Come on Hermione
拉卡隆依佛摩瑞
Lacarnum Inflamarae
着火了
Fire
你身上着火了
You're on fire
加油
Go go go go
他好像快要吐了
Looks like he's gonna be sick
他抢到金探子了
He's got the Snitch
哈利波特抢到金探子 得到了150分
Harry Potter receives 150 points for catching the Snitch
葛来分多获胜
Gryffindor wins
好
Yes
胡说八道
Nonsense
斯内普干嘛诅咒哈利的扫帚
Why would Snape put a curse on Harry's broom
谁知道
Who knows
他在万圣节晚上为何想通过三头巨犬
Why was he trying to get past that three headed dog
谁告诉你毛毛的事
Who told you about Fluffy
毛毛
Fluffy
那怪物还有名字啊
That thing has a name
当然有名字 他是我的狗
Of course he has a name He's mine
我去年在酒吧向一个爱尔兰人买的
I bought him off an Irishman
后来借给邓布利多看守 什么
I lent him to Dumbledore to guard Yes
不能说 别再问了
Shouldn't have said that
别问了 这是最高机密
No more questions That's top secret
但是 海格 斯内普想偷毛毛看守的东西
But whatever Fluffy's guarding Snape's trying to steal it
胡说八道
Codswallop
斯内普是霍格沃茨的老师
Professor Snape is a Hogwarts teacher
不管他是不是老师
Hogwarts teacher or not
我一看就知道他在下咒
I know a spell when
咒语的书我都看过
I see one I've read all about them
眼睛要紧盯着目标 斯内普完全没眨过眼
You've got to keep eye contact and Snape wasn't blinking
就是这样
Exactly
你们三个都给我听好
Now you listen to me all three of you
这件事轮不到你们来管
You're meddling in things that ought not to be meddled in
太危险了
It's dangerous
那只狗看守的东西是
What that dog is guarding is between
邓布利多和尼乐勒梅的秘密
Dumbledore and Nicholas Flamel
尼乐勒梅
Nicholas Flamel
我不小心说溜了嘴
I shouldn't have said that
I should not have said that
尼乐勒梅
Nicholas Flamel
尼乐勒梅是谁
Who's Nicholas Flamel
我不知道
I don't know
耶诞快乐
Merry Christmas
敲响霍格沃茨的钟
Ring the Hogwart bell
Cast a Christmas spell
骑士向东移五步
Knight to E 5
皇后向东移五步
Queen to E 5
真野蛮
That's totally barbaric
那是巫师棋
That's wizard's chess
你打包好了
I see you've packed
你没打包
I see you haven't
计划改变了 我爸妈要去罗马尼亚找我哥哥查理
Change of plans My parents went to Romania to visit my brother Charlie
他在那里研究龙
He's studying dragons there
好吧 那你可以帮帮哈利
Good You can help Harry
他要去图书馆 查尼乐勒梅的资料
He's going to the library to look up Nicholas Flamel
我们查过不下百次
We've looked a hundred times
禁书区还没查
Not in the restricted section
耶诞快乐
Happy Christmas
她好像被我们带坏了
I think we've had a bad influence on her
哈利 醒一醒
Harry wake up Come on
哈利 快醒醒
Harry wake up
耶诞快乐 哈利
Happy Christmas Harry
耶诞快乐 荣恩
Happy Christmas Ron
你穿的是什么
What are you wearing
我妈织的毛衣
Oh my mum made it
你好像也有一件
Looks like you've got one too
我有礼物
I've got presents
对啊
Yeah
在那边
There they are
这是你父亲临死前留下的
Your father left this in my possession before he died
现在该交还给你了
It is time it was returned to you
好好使用吧
Use it well
那是什么
What is it
好像是斗篷
Some kind of cloak
试穿看看
Well let's see then Put it on
我的身体不见了
My body's gone
我知道了 那是隐形斗篷
I know what that is That's an invisibility cloak
我隐形了吗
I'm invisible
这种斗篷很罕见
They're really rare
是谁送给你的
I wonder who gave it to you
没有署名
There was no name
只说
It just said
好好使用
Use it well
禁书区
知名吞火人
Famous Fire Eaters
十五世纪恶魔
Fifteenth Century Fiends
勒梅
Flamel
尼乐勒梅
Nicholas Flamel
到底在哪里
Where are you
是谁
Who's there
我知道你在里面
I know you're in there
你躲不了的
You can't hide
是谁
Who is it
快出来
Show yourself
斯内普 我
Severus I
你不想和我为敌吧 奇洛
You don't want me as your enemy Quirrell
我不懂你的意思
I don't know what you mean
你心知肚明
You know perfectly well what I mean
有空再聊
We'll have another little chat soon
先等你决定究竟要对谁效忠
When you've had time to decide where your loyalties lie
两位教授
Professors
这是我在禁书区检到的
I found this in the restricted section
还是热呼呼的
It's still hot
有学生偷溜下床了
That means there's a student out of bed
妈
Mum
爸
Dad
荣恩 你快来看啊
Ron you've really gotta see this
Ron you've gotta see this
荣恩 快起床
Ron come on get out of bed
干嘛
Why
你快来看 快点啦
There's something you've got to see Come on
快点
Come
你过来看 是我爸妈
Come look it's my parents
我只看见我们俩
I only see us
这样不对 站过去那边
Look in properly Go on stand there
好了 有没有看见他们
There You see them don't you
那是我 我变成级长了
That's me Only I'm head boy
手里拿着魁地奇奖杯
And I'm holding the Quidditch Cup
我也当上了魁地奇队长
And bloody hell I'm Quidditch captain too
我好威风
I look good
哈利 这面镜子 是显示未来吗
Harry do you think this mirror shows the future
怎么可能
How can it
我爸妈都死了
Both my parents are dead
又回来了吗 哈利
Back again Harry
你和以前那些人一样
I see that you like many before you
都发现了意若思镜的乐趣
Have discovered the delights of the Mirror of Erised
相信你已经知道镜子的功用了
I trust by now you realize what it does
我给你一点暗示
Let me give you a clue
世上最快乐的人
The happiest man on earth
才能在镜中 看到自己的真实面貌
Would look in the mirror and see only himself exactly as he is
镜子反映出的是 我们的欲望吗
So then it shows us what we want
所有的欲望吗
Whatever we want
对
Yes
也不对
And no
镜子反映出的正是
It shows us nothing more or less
我们内心深处最渴望的事
Than the deepest and most desperate desires of our hearts
哈利 你没见过家人
Now you Harry who have never known your family
现在看到他们站在你身边
You see them standing beside you
但记住 哈利
But remember this Harry
这面镜子
This mirror
不能提供我们知识或真相
Gives us neither knowledge or truth
人类在镜子前虚掷光阴
Men have wasted away in front of it
甚至因此而发疯
Even gone mad
所以明天要把镜子 搬去别的地方
That is why tomorrow it will be moved to a new home
请你千万
And I must ask you
别再来找这面镜子了
Not to go looking for it again
人不能活在梦里
It does not do to dwell on dreams
而遗忘了现实生活
and forget to live
我害你们找错地方了
I had you looking in the wrong section
我怎么这么笨
How could I be so stupid
这是我几周前借来消遣的书
I checked this out weeks ago for a bit of light reading
这算是消遣
This is light
当然了你们看
Of course Here it is
尼乐勒梅是世上唯一能制造出
Nicholas Flamel is the only known maker
魔法石的人
Of the Sorcerer's Stone
制造出什么
The what
真是的 你们平常不看书吗
Honestly don't you two read
魔法石是一种传说中
The Sorcerer's Stone is a legendary substance
具有惊人魔力的石头
With astonishing powers
能把金属变成纯金
It'll transform any metal into pure gold
还能制造长生不死药
And produces the Elixir of Life
喝了就能长生不死
Which will make the drinker immortal
长生不死
Immortal
就是永远不会死
It means you'll never die
这我当然知道
I know what it means
现存唯一的魔法石
The only Stone currently in existence
是属尼乐勒梅先生所有
Belongs to Mr Nicholas Flamel
他是著名的炼金术士
The noted alchemist who
去年刚满665岁
last year celebrated his 665th birthday
这就是毛毛在三楼看守的宝物
That's what Fluffy's guarding
活板门底下藏的就是魔法石
That's what's under the trap door The Sorcerer's Stone
海格 你好
Hagrid Hello
抱歉 不好意思
Sorry don't wish to be rude
但今天没心情玩
but I'm in no state to entertain
我们知道魔法石的事了
We know about the Sorcerer's Stone
斯内普想偷魔法石
We think Snape's trying to steal it
斯内普
Snape
天哪 你们居然还在谈他
Are you still on about him
海格 他想偷魔法石 只是不知他为何要偷
Hagrid We know he's after it We don't know why
斯内普可是保护魔法石的其中一位老师
Snape is one of the teachers protecting the Stone
他才不会偷魔法石 什么
He won't steal it What
你听清楚了
You heard
好了啦 我今天有点忙
Come on I'm a bit preoccupied today
等一下 你刚说其中一位老师
Wait a minute One of the teachers
没错 一定还有用别的方法 在保护魔法石对不对
There are other things defending the Stone aren't there
像是咒语啦 魔法啦
Spells enchantments
对 但我觉得这是浪费时间
Right Waste of bloody time if you ask me
没人过得了毛毛那一关
Ain't no one gonna get past Fluffy
只有我和邓布利多对付得了它
Ain't a soul knows how except for me and Dumbledore
我又不小心说溜了嘴
I shouldn't have told you that I should not have told you that
海格 那是什么
Hagrid what exactly is that
这个啊 这是
That It's
这是
Is
我知道那是什么
I know what that is
海格 你怎么弄到的
But Hagrid how did you get one
我在酒吧里 从陌生人手中赢来的
I won it Off a stranger I met down at the pub
看来好像是个烫手山芋
Seemed quite glad to be rid of it as a matter of fact
那是
Is that
一只龙吗
A dragon
不只是龙 还是挪威脊背龙了
That's not just a dragon That's a Norwegian Ridgeback
我哥哥查理在罗马尼亚研究龙
My brother works with these in Romania
很漂亮吧
Isn't he beautiful
了不起 它认识妈妈了
Oh bless him Look he knows his mummy
你好 萝卜
Hello Norbert
萝卜
Norbert
总得替它取个名字
He's gotta have a name don't he
对吧 萝卜
Don't you Norbert
它要先受点训练才行
He'll have to be trained up a bit of course
那是谁
Who's that
马尔福
Malfoy
天哪
Oh dear
海格早就想养龙了
Hagrid always wanted a dragon
第一次见面时他就说了
Told me so the first time I met him
真荒唐
It's crazy
更糟的是被马尔福知道了
And worse Malfoy knows
我不懂 有那么糟吗
I don't understand Is that bad
糟透了
It's bad
晚安
Good evening
无论如何 我重复一遍 无论如何
Nothing I repeat nothing
学生都不能在半夜四处乱跑
gives a student the right to walk about at night
我要惩罚你们的行为扣五十分
Therefore as punishment for your actions 50 points will be taken
五十分 每个人
50 Each
为了保证你们不会再犯
To ensure it doesn't happen again
罚你们四个人劳动服务
All four of you will receive detention
对不起 教授
Excuse me professor
可能是我听错了
Perhaps I heard you wrong
你说的是 四个人 吗
I thought you said the four of us
你听得没错 马尔福先生
No you heard me correctly
虽然你是出于善意
Honorable as your intentions were
可是你也在熄灯后偷溜下床
You too were out of bed after hours
你必须和他们一起接受处分
You will join your classmates in detention
可惜现在的处罚没以前严苛了
A pity they let the old punishments die
以前在受罚的时候
Was a time detention found you hanging
会把你用拇指吊在地牢里
By your thumbs in the dungeons
天哪 真怀念那时候的惨叫声
God I miss the screaming
你们今晚要和海格 一起进行劳动服务
You'll be serving detention with Hagrid tonight
他有点事要办
He's got a little job
要去黑森林
To do inside the Dark Forest
你真倒霉 海格
A sorry lot this Hagrid
天哪
Good God
你还在为那只龙的事生气吗
You're not still on about that bloody dragon are you
萝卜走了
Norbert's gone
邓布利多把它送去罗马尼亚
Dumbledore sent him off to Romania
和其它同类一起住
To live in a colony
这不是很好吗
That's good isn't it
它可以和同类在一起
He's with his own kind
但他若不喜欢 罗马尼亚怎么办
What if he don't like Romania
如果别的龙对它不好了
What if the other dragons are mean to him
它毕竟还只是小宝宝
He's only a baby
拜托 请你克制一下情绪
For God's sake pull yourself together
你还要进森林办事了
You're going into the Forest
到时候得全神贯注才行
Got to have your wits about you
森林 我还以为是在开玩笑
The Forest I thought that was a joke
那里是禁区
We can't go in there
学生不能进去
Students aren't allowed
那里有
And there are
狼人
Werewolves
喔 森林里有的可不只是狼人
There's more than werewolves in those trees
这点倒是可以确定
You can be sure of that
晚安
Nighty night
好了
Right
我们走吧
Let's go
海格 那是什么
Hagrid what is that
这就是我们来的目的
What we're here for
看见没
See that
那是独角兽的血
That's unicorn blood that is
我几个礼拜前发现一具尸体
I found one dead a few weeks ago
现在 这只独角兽伤得很严重
Now this one's been hurt bad by something
所以 我们的任务就是找到那只可怜的独角兽
So it's our job to go and find the poor beast
荣恩 赫敏 跟我来吧
Ron Hermione come with me
哈利 你和马尔福一组
And Harry you'll go with Malfoy
那我带牙牙一起去
Okay Then I get Fang
好吧
Fine
不过你要小心 它是个胆小鬼
Just so you know he's a bloody coward
要是被我爸听到你就惨了
Wait till my father hears about this
那是仆人的工作
This is servant's stuff
要是我没猜错的话
If I didn't know better
你显然是在害怕
I'd say you were scared
我才不怕了 波特
I'm not scared Potter
你听见没
Do you hear that
走吧 牙牙
Come on Fang
害怕
Scared
怎么了 牙牙
What is it Fang
救命啊
Help
哈利波特 你必须离开这里
Harry Potter you must leave
这里很多动物都认识你
You are known to many creatures here
这时候的森林不太安全
The Forest is not safe at this time
你来这里尤其危险
Especially for you
刚才要攻击我的是什么
What was that thing you saved me from
一只怪物
A monstrous creature
杀死独角兽是滔天大罪
It is a terrible crime to slay a unicorn
喝独角兽的血可以保住性命
Drinking its blood will keep you alive even
就算垂死的人也救得回来
If you are an inch from death
但必须付出惨痛的代价
But at a terrible price
因为你杀死的是纯洁的生命
For you have slain something so pure
从它的血碰触你的嘴唇 那一刻起
That the moment the blood touches your lips
你就会变得半死不活
You will have a half life
拥有受诅咒的生命
A cursed life
谁会想过这种生活了
Who would choose such a life
你想不到是谁吗
Can you think of no one
你的意思是
Do you mean to say
杀死那只独角兽
That thing that killed the unicorn
又喝了它的血的怪物
That was drinking its blood
就是佛地魔吗
That was Voldemort
你知不知道此刻在学校里
Do you know what is hidden in the school
藏了什么秘密
At this very moment
魔法石
The Sorcerer's Stone
哈利
Harry
你好啊 翡冷翠
Hello there Firenze
看来你已经见过小波特了
See you've met our young Mr Potter
你没事吧 哈利
You all right there Harry
哈利波特
Harry Potter
我们就在这里告别吧
This is where I leave you
你现在安全了
You're safe now
祝你好运
Good luck
你是说那个人就在那里
You mean You Know Who is out there right now in the Forest
就在森林里
But he's weak
可是他很虚弱 只能靠独角兽的血维生
He's living off the unicorns
你们还不懂吗
Don't you see
我们猜错了
We had it wrong
斯内普不是要把魔法石 占为己有
Snape doesn't want the Stone for himself
他是要偷来献给佛地魔
He wants it for Voldemort
有了长生不死药
With the Elixir of Life
佛地魔又可以恢复力量了
Voldemort will be strong again
他还会再回来报仇
He'll come back
他要是回来的话
But if he comes back
他该不会是想杀死你吧
You don't think he'll try to kill you do you
如果被他逮到机会 他说不定今晚就会来杀我
If he'd had the chance he might have tried tonight
亏我还在担心 魔药学的期末考了
And to think I've been worrying about my Potions final
等一下 我们忘了一件事
Hang on a minute We're forgetting one thing
谁是佛地魔向来最怕的巫师
Who's the one wizard Voldemort always feared
邓布利多
Dumbledore
只要有邓布利多在 哈利 你就不会有危险
As long as Dumbledore is around Harry you're safe
只要有邓布利多在就没人伤得了你
As long as Dumbledore is around you can't be touched
我以前就常听人说霍格沃茨的期末考很难
I'd heard Hogwarts' final exams were frightful
可是我倒觉得很轻松
but I found that enjoyable
只有你才这么觉得
Speak for yourself
你还好吧 哈利
All right there Harry
我的疤痕
My scar
一直痛得像火烧似的
It keeps burning
以前也发生过这种情况
It's happened before
没这么痛过啊
Not like this
还是带你去找护士吧
You should see the nurse
我觉得这是一种警告
I think it's a warning
表示会有危险
It means danger's coming
没错 怎么了
Of course What is it
你们不觉得奇怪吗
Isn't it odd that what
海格一直想养龙
Hagrid wants more than anything is a dragon
突然就出现带着龙蛋的陌生人
And a stranger just happens to have one
有多少人会带着龙蛋 到处走动
How many people wander around with dragon eggs
我怎么没早点想到了
Why didn't I see it before
海格 那个龙蛋是谁给你的
Who gave you the egg
他长什么样子
What did he look like
我不知道 没看清楚他的脸
I never saw his face
他一直用斗篷遮着
He kept his hood up
你有和这个陌生人交谈过吧
You and this stranger must have taliked
他问我饲养过哪些动物
He wanted to know what sort of creatures I looked after
我告诉他：养了毛毛以后
I said After Fluffy
就算养龙也绝对不成问题
A dragon's gonna be no problem
他对毛毛很兴趣吗
Was he interested in Fluffy
他当然对毛毛很感兴趣
Of course he was interested
又不是到处都看得到三头巨犬
How often do you come across a three headed dog
就连稀有动物贩子也不常看到
可是我告诉他
But I told him
驯服野兽的秘诀就是想法子让它镇定下来
The trick with any beast is to know how to calm him
就拿毛毛来说吧
Take Fluffy for example
演奏音乐给它听它马上就会睡着了
Play him music and he falls straight to sleep
我又说溜了嘴
I shouldn't have told you that
你们要去哪里 你们要去哪里
Where are you going
我们要找邓布利多教授
We have to see Dumbledore
事不宜迟
Immediately
邓布利多教授不在这里
I'm afraid he's not here
魔法部派猫头鹰送急件给他 他就立刻启程前往伦敦
He received an urgent owl from the Ministry of Magic and left
他真的走了吗
He's gone
可是我们有要紧的事
But this is important
是关于魔法石
This is about the Sorcerer's Stone
你们怎么会知道 有人想偷走魔法石
How do you know  Someone's going to try and steal it
我不知道你们三个人 怎么知道魔法石的事
I don't know how you know
这件事一直是保密到家
but I assure you it is well protected
快回去寝室吧
Now would you go back to your dormitories
尽量别出声
Quietly
海格在村子里 遇到的不是陌生人
That was no stranger Hagrid met
那个人是斯内普
It was Snape
他知道怎样通过毛毛那一关了
Which means he knows how to get past Fluffy
邓布利多又不在
And with Dumbledore gone
午安
Good afternoon
你们三个葛来分多学院的 小朋友
What would three young Gryffindors
天气这么好 怎么没出去玩
Be doing inside on a day like this
我们只是在  你们要小心一点
We were just You ought to be careful
别人可能会以为
People will think you're
你们在打什么坏主意
Up to something
现在该怎么办
Now what do we do
我们从活板门下去
We go down the trap door
今天晚上就去
Tonight
吹宝
Trevor
快走吧 你不应该来这里
Go You shouldn't be here
你们也不应该来
Neither should you
你们又偷溜出来了 对吧
You're sneaking out again aren't you
奈威 听我说 我们
Neville listen We were
不行 我不准你们去
No I won't let you
葛来分多学院会被你们害惨的
You'll get Gryffindor into trouble again
我会反抗你们
I'll fight you
奈威 真的很对不起
Neville I'm really sorry about
整整化石
This Petrificus Totalus
你有时候蛮可怕的
You're a little scary sometimes
你知道吗
You know that
很厉害 不过很可怕
Brilliant but scary
我们走吧
Let's go
对不起 这样做是为了你好
Sorry It's for your own good you know
你踩到我的脚了
You stood on my foot
对不起
Sorry
阿洛哈姆啦
Alohomora
等一下 它
Wait a minute He's
有鼾声
Snoring
斯内普已经来了
Snape's already been here
他对竖琴下了咒
He's put a spell on the harp
它的嘴巴好臭
It's got horrible breath
必须把它的脚掌移开
We have to move its paw
什么
What
快来
Come on
好了 用力推
Okay Push
我先走
I'll go first
等我发信号再跟过来
Don't follow until I give you a sign
要是情况不妙
If something bad happens
你们就自己逃命吧
Get yourselves out
你们有没有觉得好安静
Does it seem a bit quiet to you
竖琴
The harp
竖琴停止演奏了
It's stopped playing
跳啊
Jump
幸好有这株植物挡住
Lucky this plant thing's here really
你们俩别再乱动了
Stop moving both of you
这是魔鬼网
This is Devil's Snare
你们别太紧张
You have to relax
要不然就会死得更快
If you don't it will only kill you faster
死得更快
Kill us faster
这下子我就不紧张了
Oh now I can relax
赫敏
Hermione
现在该怎么办
Now what are we gonna do
只管放轻松
Just relax
赫敏 你在哪里
Hermione where are you
照着我的话做
Do what I say
相信我
Trust me
哈利
Harry
你没事吧
Are you okay
没事 我很好
Yeah I'm fine
他没放轻松 对吧
He's not relaxing is he
显然没有
Apparently not
一定要想个办法 什么办法
We've gotta do something What
还记得我在药草学的书上看过
I remember reading something in Herbology
魔鬼网 魔鬼网
Devil's Snare Devil's Snare
它会致人于死
It's deadly fun
可是晒到阳光就完蛋了
But will sulk in the sun That's it
对了 恶魔网讨厌阳光
It hates sunlight
灿灿光
Lumus Solem
荣恩 你没事吧
Ron you okay
没事
Yeah
幸好我们没惊慌失措
Lucky we didn't panic
幸好赫敏上药草学课时很认真
Lucky Hermione pays attention in Herbology
那是什么声音
What is that
我不知道
I don't know
好像是翅膀挥动的声音
Sounds like wings
真奇怪
Curious
我没看过这种鸟
I've never seen birds like these
那不是鸟 是钥匙
They're not birds They're keys
一定有把钥匙可以打开那扇门
And I'll bet one of them fits that door
这是怎么回事
What's this all about
我不知道
I don't know
真奇怪
Strange
阿洛哈姆啦
Alohomora
试试看也无妨
Well it was worth a try
现在怎么办
What will we do
那里有上千把钥匙
There must be a thousand keys
我们要找的是一把老式大钥匙
We want a big old fashioned
可能像门把一样生锈了
One Probably rusty
在那里 我看到了
That I see it
翅膀受伤的那把钥匙
The one with the broken wing
怎么了 哈利
What's wrong Harry
太不费吹灰之力了
It's too simple
去吧 哈利
Go on Harry
如果斯内普用旧扫帚追得上它
If Snape could catch it on that old broomstick you can
那你也办得到 你可是百年来最年轻的搜捕手
You're the youngest Seeker in a century
事情变得有点复杂了
This complicates things a bit
抓住那把钥匙
Catch the key
快点
Hurry up
我觉得不太对劲
I don't like this
实在是太不对劲了
I don't like this at all
这是哪里
Where are we
墓地
A graveyard
这才不是墓地
This is no graveyard
这是西洋棋盘
It's a chessboard
门在那里
There's the door
现在怎么办
Now what do we do
不是很明显吗
It's obvious isn't it
要下棋才能通过这个房间
We've got to play our way across the room
哈利 你站在主教那个空格里
Harry you take the empty bishop's square
赫敏 你就当皇后旁边的城堡吧
Hermione you'll be the queen side castle
至于我
As for me
我来当骑士
I'll be a knight
现在了
What happens now
嗯 白棋先移动
Well white moves first
然后
And then
换我们出招了
We play
荣恩
Ron
你该不会以为
You don't suppose this is going to be like
真的是在玩巫师西洋棋吧
Real wizard's chess do you
你移到D5
You there D 5
对 赫敏
Yes Hermione
我觉得这和巫师西洋棋完全一模一样
I think this is gonna be exactly like wizard's chess
城堡移到E4
Castle to E 4
卒子移到C3
Pawn to C 3
等一下
Wait a minute
你明白了吧 哈利
You understand right Harry
只要我一移动 皇后就会把我吃掉
Once I make my move the queen will take me
这样你就可以趁机进攻国王
Then you're free to check the king
荣恩 不行啊
No Ron no
怎么了
What is it
他要牺牲自己
He's going to sacrifice himself
不行 一定还有别的办法
No there must be another way
你到底想不想 阻止斯内普偷走魔法石
Do you wanna stop Snape from getting that Stone or not
哈利 你必须继续前进
Harry it's you that has to go on
我觉得该去的人
I know it
不是我 不是赫敏 而是你
Not me Not Hermione You
骑士移到H3
Knight to H 3
将军
Check
荣恩
Ron
不 别乱动
No don't move
别忘了我们还在下棋
Don't forget we're still playing
死棋
Checkmate
好好照顾荣恩
Take care of Ron
然后去找猫头鹰
Then go to the owlery
寄封信给邓布利多
Send a message to Dumbledore
荣恩说得对
Ron's right
我必须继续前进
I have to go on
你不会有事的 哈利
You'll be okay Harry
你是伟大的魔法师
You're a great wizard
我真的这么觉得
You really are
我才比不上你了
Not as good as you
我 只是靠书本和小聪明
Me Books and cleverness
但还有些更重要的条件
There are more important things
友爱和勇气
Friendship and bravery
哈利 你要小心一点
And Harry just be careful
是你
You
不 不可能
No it can't be
斯内普 他才是
Snape he was the
对 他看起来一脸坏相对吧
Yes he does seem the type doesn't he
所以了 有他在身边
Next to him who would suspect
谁还会怀疑口吃的奇洛教授
Poor stuttering Professor Quirrell
可是魁地奇比赛那天
But that day during the Quidditch match
斯内普还想害死我
Snape tried to kill me
你错了 亲爱的孩子
No dear boy
想杀你的人是我
I tried to kill you
相信我要不是斯内普的斗篷着了火
If Snape's cloak hadn't caught fire
害得我没办法死盯着你
And broken my eye contact
我早就成功了
I would have succeeded
斯内普念再多解咒语也没用
Even with Snape muttering his countercurse
斯内普想救我
Snape was trying to save me
我一开始就看出你会威胁到我
I knew you were a danger to me
尤其是在万圣节过后
Especially after Halloween
所以你就把山怪放进来
Then you let the troll in
算你厉害 波特 答对了
Very good Potter yes
可惜斯内普没上我的当
Snape unfortunately wasn't fooled
其它人都在地牢里四处乱鼠
While everyone ran about
他却跑去三楼想拦住我
He went to the third floor to head me off
当然他再也不会相信我了
He of course never trusted me again
他几乎不让我一个人独处
He rarely left me alone
只是他没搞清楚
But he doesn't understand
我从来都不是一个人
I'm never alone Never
现在
Now
这面镜子是干嘛用的
what does this mirror do
我能看到自己想要的东西
I see what I desire
我看到自己手里拿着魔法石
I see myself holding the Stone
可是我是怎么拿到的
But how do I get it
利用那个男孩
Use the boy
给我过来 波特
Come here Potter
快点
Now
告诉我
Tell me
你看见了什么
What do you see
What is it What do you see
我在和邓布利多握手
I'm shaking hands with Dumbledore
我赢得了学院杯冠军
I've won the house cup
他说谎
He lies
跟我说实话
Tell the truth
你看见了什么
What do you see
让我和他谈谈
Let me speak to him
主人 你还没恢复力量
Master you are not strong enough
我的力量足以应付得了
I have strength enough for this
哈利波特
Harry Potter
我们又见面了
We meet again
佛地魔
Voldemort
没错
Yes
看到我现在的模样了吧
You see what I've become
你知道我要怎样求生了吧
See what I must do to survive
靠别人活下去活像是个寄生虫
Live off another A mere parasite
独角兽的血可以让我延续生命
Unicorn blood can sustain me
但却无法让我得到自己的身体
But it cannot give me a body of my own
不过还有别的办法
But there is something that can
那件垂手可得的东西 就在你的口袋里
Something that conveniently enough lies in your pocket
阻止他
Stop him
别傻了
Don't be a fool
你可以和我一起活下去 又何必冒险惨死了
Why suffer an horrific death when you can join me and live
休想
Never
真勇敢
Bravery
你爸妈也很勇敢
Your parents had it too
告诉我
Tell me
哈利
Harry
想不想再见到你爸妈
Would you like to see your mother and father again
只要我们合作
Together
就能让他们起死回生
we can bring them back
我只要求一样东西作为回报
All I ask is for something in return
面对现实吧 哈利
That's it Harry
世上并没有绝对的善与恶
There is no good and evil
差别只是在于强者
There is only power
和无法认清事实的弱者之分
And those too weak to seek it
只要我们合作 一定能有非凡的成就
Together we'll do extraordinary things
把魔法石交给我
Just give me the Stone
你这个骗子
You liar
杀了他
Kill him
这是什么魔法
What is this magic
白痴 快去拿魔法石
Fool get the Stone
早日康复
午安 哈利
Good afternoon Harry
这是仰慕者送你的礼物吗
Tokens from your admirers
仰慕者
Admirers
你和奇洛教授在地牢里的事百分之百完全保密
What happened in the dungeons between you and Professor Quirrell is a secret
所以全校师生自然全都知道了
So naturally the whole school knows
看来你那位朋友荣恩
I see that your friend Ronald has saved you the trouble
替你省了拆开巧克力蛙的麻烦
Of opening your Chocolate Frogs
荣恩也在 他没事吧
Ron was here Is he all right
赫敏了
What about Hermione
没事
Fine
他们俩都安然无恙
They're both just fine
但那魔法石了
What happened to the Stone
别紧张 我亲爱的孩子
Relax dear boy
魔法石已经被摧毁了
The Stone has been destroyed
我和好友尼乐聊了一会儿
My friend Nicholas and I have had a little chat
我们认为这是最妥善的做法
And agreed it was best all around
不过尼乐勒梅就会死了
But then Flamel he'll die won't he
他还存了些长生不死药够他们把事情安排妥当
He has enough Elixir to set his affairs in order
不过 没错
But yes
他终究还是会死
He will die
魔法石怎么会落到我手上
How is it I got the Stone sir
原本我还在看着镜子 突然就
One minute I was staring in the mirror and
你还不明白吗 任何人
You see only a person
只有真心想找到魔法石
Who wanted to find the Stone find it
而不是存心要拿来用的人才能得到魔法石
But not use it would be able to get it
这是我想出来的好方法
That is one of my more brilliant ideas
咱们俩合作无间才能顺水推舟达到目的
And between you and me that is saying something
这表示魔法石消失以后
Does that mean with the Stone gone that
佛地魔就再也不会回来了吗
Voldemort can never come back
我恐怕
I'm afraid
他还是有办法再回来
There are ways in which he can return
哈利 你知道为什么奎洛教授
Harry do you know why Professor Quirrell
受不了你碰触他吗
Couldn't bear to have you touch him
那是因为你母亲的缘故
It was because of your mother
她为了你牺牲了自己
She sacrificed herself for you
这类举动会留下了一个印记
And that kind of act leaves a mark
不对 这种印记是看不见的
No this kind of mark cannot be seen
它存留在你的皮肤上
It lives in your very skin
什么印记
What is it
就是爱啊 哈利
Love Harry Love
柏蒂的全口味豆
Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans
我小时候不幸吃到一颗味道很恶心的豆子
I was most unfortunate in my youth to come across a vomit flavored one
后来就再也不敢吃了
And since then I've lost my king for them
可是我想应该可以选颗
But I think I could be safe
太妃糖口味的
With a nice toffee
天哪
Alas
是耳屎
Earwax
你还好吧 荣恩
All right there Ron
我很好 你了
All right You
我很好
All right
赫敏了
Hermione
好得不得了
Never better
史莱哲林学院
又一年过去了
Another year gone
现在就我所知
And now as I understand it
我们该来颁发学院冠军杯了
The house cup needs awarding
各学院的分数如下
And the points stand thus:
第四名
In fourth place
葛来分多 312分
Gryffindor with 312 points
第三名
Third place
赫夫帕夫 352分
Hufflepuff with 352 points
第二名
In second place
雷文克劳 426分
Ravenclaw with 426 points
第一名
And in first place
得分是472分
With 472 points
史莱哲林学院
Slytherin house
干得好 同学
Nice one mate
表现得很好 史莱哲林
Yes well done Slytherin
Well done Slytherin
不过 最近有几件事也必须列入考量
However recent events must be taken into account
最后还要再加几分
And I have a few last minute points to award
赫敏 格兰杰小姐
To Miss Hermione Granger
在其它人陷入重大危难时
For the cool use of intellect
冷静地运用智慧脱困
While others were in grave peril
加五十分
50 points
干得好
Good job
其次是荣恩 韦斯莱先生
Second to Mr Ronald Weasley
最优秀的西洋棋手
For the best played game of chess
霍格沃茨多年来无人能出其右
That Hogwarts has seen these many years
加五十分
50 points
再来是
And third
哈利波特先生
To Mr Harry Potter
胆识过人 勇气可嘉
for pure nerve and outstanding courage
我再加给葛来分多学院
I award Gryffindor house
六十分
60 points
我们和史莱哲林同分了
We're tied with Slytherin
最后 要挺身而出对抗敌人的确需要很大的勇气
Finally it takes a great deal of bravery to stand up to your enemies
但若是要挺身反抗朋友 却需要更大的勇气
But a great deal more to stand up to your friends
我再加十分
I award 10 points
给奈威隆巴顿
To Neville Longbottom
如果我计算得没错
Assuming that my calculations are correct I believe
这里的装饰要改变一下了
That a change of decoration is in order
葛来分多赢得学院杯冠军
Gryffindor wins the house cup
太好了
Yes
动作快 你们快来不及了
Come on now Hurry up you'll be late
火车要开走了 快走吧
Train's leaving Go on Come on hurry up
动作快一点
Come on Hurry up
快点啊 哈利
Come on Harry
再等一下
One minute
连声再见也不说就想走啦
Thought you were leaving without saying goodbye did you
这是送给你的
This is for you
谢谢你 海格
Thanks Hagrid
去吧 快去啊 听我说 哈利
Go on On with you On with you now Oh listen Harry
如果你那个笨蛋表哥达力再敢欺负你
If that dolt of a cousin of yours Dudley gives you any grief
你就吓唬他
You could always threaten him
说要送他一对猪耳朵 好搭配他那条猪尾巴
With a nice pair of ears to go with his tail
可是我们一离开霍格沃茨就不能用魔法了
But we're not allowed to do magic away from Hogwarts
这你也知道
You know that
我是知道
I do
但你表哥可不知道
But your cousin don't do he
要回家了 感觉很奇怪吧
Feels strange to be going home doesn't it
我又不是真的要回家
I'm not going home
那才不是我的家了
Not really